so I can see here a white color the
nose plastic I will carry my sell with
me on the
[Music]
islands
for
[Music]
for Wallace
welcome vent welcome to Taiwan hello
everyone I'm very excited to be here on
William channel to talk about burgundy
today oh great great great please brief
us on the introduction of bini what I
will try to do uh during the uh few
minutes that we have together it's uh to
s simplify burgundy as much as possible
because many people think that burgundy
is really complicated but I will give
you a key u a key fact in order to make
it very easy to uh to understand if we
look at Burgundy there is lots of
different wines so many are produced so
many different names and that's why some
people are getting confused sometimes
because there is lots of different names
but in term of production it's very
small because Burundi is all about the
ter it's all about the soil about where
the grape uh is uh is from now talk
about burgundy and the fact that uh the
wines are getting more and more popular
around the world um burgundy it's a very
tiny area in France even though it's
spread out in different region with lots
of different wines uh we uh if I just
look at from maon to Shi it represent
roughly about 5% of of the French total
one production which is very small small
when you just kind of describe about Bo
we would call it 5 + one so five the
five major region would be from the very
North to the South by chronological
order so we have uh sh then k k de K
shalan and maon that's the five and then
on the very s there's bile exactly the
label of of uh the burgundy is very
complicated in the regions so can you
teach us a little bit like can you try
to simplify it a little bit and teach us
uh how to look at a Burgundian label
I'll do my best yeah okay yeah okay
let's say that here we have a pyramid
and on the pyramid on the top you have
the gr crew that basically roughly
represents between 1.4 to 2% of the
total wine production in burgundy so
we're talking about 5% of France and
then 1 to 2% of burgundy of burgundy so
that's like small small small super
small very uh little gr crew
and then you have the pr PR roughly
represent 10% of Burgundy wine
production so those two guys are always
located on the slop of of a hill then
you have the village that is on the
mainland and then you have Regional but
a grae that cannot uh that is um from
the regional area that outside the
appellation of a village cannot claim to
be a vage
or but it is in the burgundy you can
downgrade but you can never UPG never
ever so um if I if I can use those BT
that we have here to to explain for
instance I take the B P here it's mean
that this PIR can come from anywhere in
B for it's coming
from and the give you just just a quick
idea okay um it's the same thing if
we're talking about A Shard uh it can
come from anywhere in burgundy for us
it's coming from northern part of
burgundy the shab area and aart from
Coes as as you know we bought 45
hectares of Vineyard in chalz last year
so we are using our new estate as well
so is it fair to say that for shanong
their Bon Char is U more elegant the
acidity is more refreshing because most
of the charie comes from the north yeah
going towards a Elegant Style Minal
freshness exactly and also we have this
uh very good maturity that provide you
juicy fruits but we always want to have
a perfect balance regarding the type of
fruit we don't want to be to have a wine
that is um you know feeling like
sensation to be a bit fat we want
something to be vibrant yes yes and and
then most of the other uh other Bania
charie you find in the market a lot of
them is from the south and great main
okay so where it's more like heavy and
and and more um oily type stuff it's uh
a different style different style also
it's
uh sometimes a bit also cheaper to
Source from the side and from nor yes
that we know because the shev area is
very expensive here uh it's an important
wine as you will see there is a fortress
on the on the label it's signature wine
it's the first wine where many people
are going to start to try sh will be
with b p and we want them to have lots
of pleasure and to try different wines
afterwards okay so this would be a very
very good entry if we are talking uh to
the next level uh of uh labels that you
find uh in uh in burgundy uh if I'm
taking for instance sh yes here shab
will be a village that mean uh indeed
you have people that are living in this
Village and you have Vina that is on the
on the village so it's a delimited
surface area and uh if you want to have
a wine that is called Shi 100% of the
grapes must come from this area oh 100%
100 everything okay it's forbidden in
France to use uh grapes that are coming
from uh another Village and still keep
the name sh I know in some countries
they are more permissive in burgundy uh
100% Village on the label is 100% of the
grape is from that Village exactly so it
will be the the same thing when you're
moving for instance for
Merc that here means that 100% of the
grape P are coming from this Village
okay so uh really burgundi it's about uh
the plot it's about the village uh what
we want to provide you it's an
experience uh it's to be able to see
that uh even though you have two plots
next to each each other or two Villages
that are 1 km apart even though it's p
it tastes completely different
completely different even though if it's
ch that make it exactly the same way PIR
that will grow on different soil will
have a a different
expression and uh that started a long
time ago in burgundy it was due to the
work of the Sito and cian monks and they
did dedicated their life to make great
cheese and great wine and they are the
one that started to see that strangely a
Vine is producing fruit but this fruit
to make wine is better on the poor soil
on the slop not on the rich soil which
is strange because when you're making
fruit you want to reach so yeah not uh
regarding wine because uh they discover
that the roots are going down very deep
and they are anchoring into the rock
that is going to provide a different
Prof file of Aromas the minerals for
instance yeah or the or the tant will
fill a Supple or the type of black
cherry plum Cassis type of Aras will be
different from one plot to to another
looking from the region burgundi from
the area Kon and then inside the Kon
we're having a village and inside the
village there is also different
plants okay so we going even further
into uh how uh peculiar we are in uh in
the tawa and if I'm presenting you
actually one of my shushu one of my
personal which is the apple of my eye in
good English I'll show you
Peres here that's mean that you are on
the village of per viles and you're
tasting the plot that is called viles
just a little plot
that we own for instance
5.4 hectar of Vineyard which is a decent
size of uh but the specificity of this
plot here is that um VES gave the name
to the Village PR Grand crew are always
located on the slope of the Hill because
this is where you get the best ter due
to overtime erosion with rain uh so you
are very close to the Bedrock so this is
what you want you want to be close to
the to the to the Rock okay so it all
depends on the type of the slope exactly
on the Topography of the village also if
it's facing east west south uh the winds
Corridor the sun Exposition uh and also
what there is on the top of uh of the
slope so usually then Center would be
grand crew top will be Pac and at the
floor would be Rel Lush usually but
there's exactly one thing uh that uh
I've noticed okay this is for sh okay
this is one thing I noticed the label is
one of a kind uh there's so much
information on the label up to standard
with the current Trend in terms of the
looks of clean Elegance but at the same
time there's so much information on it
can you kind of let our friends know why
the label is like this or what's on the
information yeah first of all uh sh
share appreciate very much the
compliment on on our new label talking
about our new label it's very new for us
okay very new because we changed our
label this year 2 of January 2024 not
because we wanted to change the label
you know just for marketing purpose for
us it has to mark an achievement the
achievement for CH in the village there
is a different plus and here for
instance you'll be on the prier
cre PR crew and in the same time here is
it's a monopo monopo means that only sh
is the owner of this appellation and
only Shon is producing their this wine
no one else we own the whole appellation
what we wanted is to uh mark an
achievement a big achievement because we
double the size of our estate will be a
officially certified organic uh we are
the first estate in France certified
great place to work happiness and
trusting days index uh in the company
and we decided that it was time to to
Mark something as uh an evolution so we
Chang our label and we gave lots of
thoughts regarding it as you mentioned
before Willi labels could be complicated
yes so we decided for our label to
actually uh be useful simplify provide
them useful information such as for
instance the size of the plot the type
of soil also the sun exposit on the uh
on the label and the time in barrel of
course I use the only one that uh is
still a barrel uh CU this is a barrel
simple so it's still written in Barrel
in French but it will be 19 months at
the end of the aging and you have the
Vintage the name being straightforward
giving a useful information trying to
simplify indeed wow so you have
everything on it so it's 4.1 hectare it
is 19 month in barrel and it just slopes
facing the Sun and Premier crew so you
have everything on it I've also noticed
one thing uh from some of the labels a
little different from this one in the
logo here it says domain but some other
is Debut 1750s what's the difference uh
one means domain that mean that it's
part of our own 90 hectares of Vineyards
okay and another one written since 1750
uh it means that here we uh are not the
owner of the lens okay all not all yes
that being said we are harvesting and
making the wine aging the wine ourself
but the land is probably owned by
someone else but we give the same
attention for it's it's not better or
worse it's just a different we don't own
it you don't own it that's all oh very
clear tell us a little bit about um uh
Shan song's uh wine making after the
wine making and what's the difference
between a regular seller and what is a
regular seller that's that's very good
question
that's uh so talking about because this
is actually yes very unique we own a
Fess Fess that is called Bastion uh it's
a old military Fess that is dated from
Lou 11 part of the uh defense mechanism
of bone the town and uh as the town was
never attacked uh these Fess were empty
there is a five around B and um the
biggest one is ours and Sho actually
decided to create their Winer in
1750 uh one of the oldest yes one of the
three oldest uh in uh in burgundy and
they decided to settle in this part of
bone because they had the possibility to
rent this Fortress to the king so they
went to Paris and they asked the king
there is a massive military Fortress
that is we would like to make wine
inside and the King say yes you can 39
years after the French Revolution in
1789 happened and well the King was uh
behaved with alongside many other people
and uh all the king property fall into
the new Republic and Shon had the
possibility to buy the foress right
after make it their own and started to H
added more
so to give you an idea we are not going
down in the and um for us we are going
up floor by floor it's a for floor
building and the reason it's perfect to
make wine it's because we're talking
about a foress that has walls that are
between 8 to 13 m 8 to 30 m of pure
rocks 8 m is God it's like it's like
it's huge yeah it's all the thickness of
room even more even more and temperature
between winter and summer don't move
very much okay so it's almost stable
yeah the Fess is built around a column
that is the well because there's a
solder they could take water out okay
and for us that provide the natural
humidity in the for it's kind of unique
very good to visit uh actually because
uh you're going up and it is full of
History because military soldiers used
to actually live there and now sh has
been making wine in this Fortress for
270 years wow not last but not least I
think it's not the last question but I
still have to ask this question if you
have to pick one wine if it's one wine
if you can only pick one wine um what
would you consider to be the most
special one in
chel indeed this question is very very
very tricky it's like if you are alone
on an island and you have your best wine
with you uh which one will it be and I
will be like it will be fun for the
first two weeks then I'll be very
unhappy because what I like is diversity
and that's what burgundy is bringing me
but to give you my um one of my shushu
for the white in burgundy it's on the
village of Peres and I will mention
Peres PR
[Music]
the reason I love this wine is because
um many people says that maybe burgundy
is getting very expensive especially in
some areas yes I love a goodbye everyone
loves a goodbye and I like to go off the
beaten path so um I like to explore
things so you're having this profile
that is huge wine for a fraction of the
price of
uh I'm I'm GNA definitely try it so
that's for the white yeah love that for
uh for the Reds H so uh so difficult I
introduced you the um CL F earlier so
maybe I'll introduce you to another one
that I haunt very very much it is the CL
mush wa very iconic located at the
frontier at the border with P okay at
the same height with
p and same height as if should have been
a gr crew uh CL mush exist in both
colors Reds and whites we are lucky
enough to own uh in total 4.5 hectares
of vard 4.3 are in production right now
mush means fly in French old world
French we referring here to the honey
bees and it's very very famous area so
it's fair to say it's actually we call
the super Premier group in a way yep
like in bordeau there's super second
growth but I know I know you have a lot
more I will car I will carry my sell
with me on an
Islands burgundy y has become really
increasingly expensive over the past
three or four years you know around that
area and uh what is your point of view
on that as we mentioned soon now burgund
it's a very small area in France
represent 5% of French wine production
right now in the past uh let's say uh
six seven years we have been heavily
affected by global warming and when I'm
talking about uh global warming here
it's not only due to U the fact that
during the summer it's very hot and
we're having massive drw lack of water
and for us the big issue is the frost in
the past few years we had two episode of
frust that are huge one very serious
2016 and
2021 where for instance 2021 we uh
burgundy overall lost uh roughly 60% of
uh the wine production that year at Cho
we lost 65% wow so this reason is price
boomed because the demand is very high
the production is at the lowest and they
have to have the income yeah uh
regarding um the um the global warming
in term of wine quality it has been very
good so far touching wood because uh you
never know it can go to a it can go
sideways very easily but uh so far it's
been very good because it provided um
exceptional vintages one after another
the uh sad impact to have smaller yields
uh that was very corrected by Mother
Nature on the Vintage 2022 which is an
amazing vintage where Mother Nature give
us both of the best words quantity and
quality burgundy were uh was getting uh
expensive yes yes so so you know if for
newcomers it it's not going to be easy
to to spend so much if they're just
coming into trying burgundy and
understanding burgundy because it's
getting more and more expensive so do
you have any suggestions for newcomers
in burgundy there is lots of different
village lots of different wines for
people that wants to
Adventure I will uh tell them to go off
the Beaton path I will tell them to
actually be curious and um try other
alternative for instance
why are getting so expensive those are
very tiny village villages in burgundy
so lots of Demands small production
price are going up but if you go right
outside you're going to find lots of
different alternative from Villages that
are less known doesn't mean that they
are less good they are actually very
good but less known ah so I will U tell
people to actually try other Villages go
out of the one that everyone are
speaking about because there is so much
to discover and um that's one of the
reason as well that we acquired 45
hectars of Vineyard in the coach chz
exceptional ter where uh wines are
amazing and because they are less known
with very very good price so I would uh
I will recommend uh to actually uh do
like we did uh try mercur and RI at CH
we gave the same attention from a mercur
RI as we were doing RI foro or mercur
to so this one for instance yeah we are
giving same care same attention same
Barrel maker same place in the Fortress
the difference is just the pon is coming
from a differenta quality of taste is
very good it's very nice yeah you you
almost cannot distinguish clearly
between you know uh wines from the door
area and and from shalona it's very
thank you very much amazing you have a
great experience and your wallet will be
very happy as well we actually both work
on both colors on those Villages but you
are correct uh it's very wellknown
really white and mercur red okay okay
definitely you should
try okay now it's my turn to introduce a
burgundy from Tai one wait I did prepare
it and it's called Boba te okay you have
you tried it never okay well I heard
about it have you seen a straw that's
that thick no I'm expecting that there
is a few things to uh there's like
little balls of uh some very sweet
dessert inside and then with a tea and
you should try it yeah like
that and you
try all
right is is
Boba te so I can see here a white color
huh you can shake it and smell
it the nose uh
[Laughter]
[Music]
plastic it's good it is a dessert yes
cuz you actually have to chew on those
bubbles yeah it's very good it's very
good I love it yeah you don't have to
finish it but it's very good but okayy
[Music]
Mery
thank you bye bye bye thank you super
thank you great great
[Music]